so many ways is doing the same through
his own efforts his name's Chris Ronan
you know I'm alright anybody you just
got that on video for the 11 o'clock
news commercial that never is a circle
but like disintegrated
this is Cleveland and if University
circles anything it is claimants the
people in Cleveland end up my
association with cultural guidance which
had the pleasure of being and every day
to and from work and a lot of other
reasons to be there how many of you
today said the CV are somehow associated
with the rest of you how much you
appreciate that
so to is Paul burek and I never knew
that I was going to see more popular
after City Hall because we both worked
about I wonder character he'll say that
we're now in a place that we love City
Hall things City Hall we're both
veterans and expanse of it but it's
always in us but I good fortune is I see
more of albiric outside of City Hall the
name even did back then it was an honor
and a pleasure just briefly to meet his
family in the family table would you
give a wave out there tonight
to the family to dig up dirt find
anything I can know that I didn't know
about Paul but unfortunately Paul is
consistent both in his family and of
course it for us and truly fortunately
gives consistent I asked his son and
daughter but what about dad and they
said well he sadly community a lot he
gives a lot of this time he never stops
giving to the community and we know that
about you your cousin said you never let
the grass grow under your feet you're
always on the move we know that about
you and your wife finally gave you
something I didn't know about you that
Paul burka came here as a young kid to a
community to a country that welcomes him
and he knew very few words in the
English language I also and good humor
learned that you didn't know what a hot
dog was and you were afraid you'd have
one but you had one anyways he became an
American and again and this is the
family here tonight and your family
extended in Cleveland who honor you Paul
for the person you are inconsistent
giver a doer an activist in the
Cleveland community in Greater Cleveland
so it's my honor as someone who served
in City Hall to introduce Paul burek
tonight and to help bring him into the
Hall of Fame I do want to say to Dan and
Debbie thank you for all you do your
mom's gonna be proud of you guys it's
all right here Cleveland people Rock and
Roll Hall of Fame stars come and go they
come and get their award across the mall
and sometimes in New York it would put
them up in the Hall and we go pay our
respects but I think of the Hall of
Fame's this is the Hall of Fame that
really matters in Cleveland at your 2016
100th anniversary the cleveland cultural
guarantee at the pleasure to speak dr.
curries here tonight and those who came
before him and we said them that
Leo ye fall vision to have a garden that
would reflect all of Cleveland's people
I'm so glad you brought it up tonight
and it was that Shakespeare garden that
was the first garden in the park and it
was William Shakespeare himself who said
one of the city but it's people I think
that is what we're all about the people
of Cleveland are what make this place
and Paul Barrett really epitomizes who
we are as Clevelanders um he is a
connector
he's an educator and he is an advocate
and totally at City Hall council member
I can tell and it's uh councilman
Zimmerman earlier former councilman San
Fermin that we all sort of unforce all
too often at the hall found ourselves in
pipelines the engineers would work in
one corner the planners where I worked
in another corner in the designers in
another corner
kapal as an architect designer and
somebody who cared
petrulio bridge he would bridge between
floors he would bridge between
departments he was a communicator
educator advocate of character he cares
about the big picture and he cares about
the small details and that's what you're
brought to I guess your second career at
the cultural garden Federation Paul was
born in the city of Babar yes the
namesake of Budweiser beer automated to
Czech Republic this bath last fall
actually saw that beer hat that here and
then didn't make it over to book market
far as everything hurt and what is now a
Czech Republic he and his father came
over in 1968 episode animation the
attended Kent State University where he
received a degree in architecture and he
spent much of his professional career as
I said at Cleveland City Hall
I remember him on the Landmarks
Commission and streetscape committee
again minding the details and bridging
people and finding away if it's not this
way or that way it was the third way
that Paul burek helped us see another
way to get things done we need more of
that these days and Paul you talks is
now very active as you know with the
cultural gardens has
very active as a past president of the
umbrella organization that you represent
30 and growing national gardens and
currently serves as vice president is
chapter president of spas Betty opening
easier notice SBU took Slovak Society of
Arts and Sciences organization dedicated
to advancing the understanding of
Czechoslovakian ruski cultures I will
stay on the centennial anniversary that
you hosted us in this past two summers
ago it was once again a bridge very
mindful of three unique cultures
connected together and he bogeyed that
on the day that we spent with you in the
park thank you for being the bridge
across our ethnicities and in that case
of Czechoslovakia LaRussa Paulus also a
member of so great a Cleveland Czech
atletic and cultural organization where
he serves on the cultural committee is a
member of the Cleveland Brown Slava
sister cities and kavadlo Bruceton
Society
in his hometown has any time left in the
town of Avon of hope Eric is a past
president the French Creek foundation an
organization which he co-founded
twenty-five years ago to improve and
promote the downtown area day one and
you're succeeding by the way that I've
seen he also serves as chairman of the
Planning Commission they're developing
the town's master planning zoning
regulations so I guess the operative
tonight on top of your dad your husband
your nephew your cousin being consistent
he's always giving thank you to the
family for giving Paul burek and
therefore his time to us of this
community to the family of the girls do
you guys
[Music]
as community Lorraine sailing in the
Yacht Club teaching sailing is a
passenger Commodore Feist Commodore
encounter of that club and with his wife
of a friend their combined family of
five adult children eight grandchildren
who we've introduced a few of and
cousins aunts and uncles they all enjoy
also kind of apologize gardening cooking
traveling with them he's a true true
public servant the one who remembers the
service side of public service the one
who remembers that we are all ultimately
as Clevelanders after similar goals for
our community but he's a bridge builder
he's a connector he's an educator and
he's an advocate he's an advocate for
what this is all about Cleveland people
and our glorious diversity Paul Europe
[Applause]
well thank you for the award and what
makes it really special to me is that
else introduced like this from a
colleague and a friend and thank you
Chris for presentation so thank you for
that and then she I do to thank so many
people so whom may have done things
along the way question arezzo great
Directioners late and I know you think
that Congress Lee there were situations
were people made comments or good action
they probably never knew so many that
they were for example when I was
studying architecture
[Music]
and what we're trying to do it's a voice
you're drawing silent voice that can
speak for me and it would slam ha the
desperate poverty grouper that he carry
around furniture were up and pay
attention and and then Hammond
repeatedly some number of times and it
resonated you may have
and it still does as years added on
standby I realize not just the drawings
but it's all the work that that we are
learning that is doing and so it kinda
morphed into all the work is your voice
it shall speak for you
and that was my guiding principles
principle so of course as Chris pointed
out I do need to thank my family
probably speaking for most people on the
board myself we have done other things
spend a lot of time went to meetings
planning meetings planning events going
to events and being brutally honest or
or families paid price so I do want to
point out the immediate family friend
Urich my wife has been by my side those
of you who know me know friend because
but it's adapting the garments or in a
bomb or Rovere over she she said she say
[Applause]